## Khurram Shehzad

Mobile: +92 343 5220 225

E-Mail: khurram.pak522@gmail.com

Skype: khurram.shehzad1822

Linkedin: khurram-shehzad-4bb38918

Github: khurram18

## Summary

I am an experienced native iOS and Android application developer and have total 9+ years in mobile development with 6+ years in iOS development and 4+ in Android development. I have used Swift, Kotlin, Objective-C and Java programming languages for mobile application development.

## Professional Experience

• Luminary Podcasts (Sep 2018 - Jan 2020)

Mobile Application Developer

- I was part of team that developed iOS and android app of Luminary. Luminary is a podcasts broadcasting and streaming platform from New York having \$200M VC Funding. Please see the iOS app <u>here</u> and Android app <u>here</u>.
- Devcrew (Sep 2016 Aug 2018)

Mobile Application Developer

Devcrew is a software development house and during my stay I worked on below mentioned apps.

- Atlas Faith Journeys: This is an android app as part of TBN organisation and can be found <u>here</u>.
- Glo Bible App: This is an iOS app for reading Bible. It provides excellent reading experience, along with multi media content support. For details please see here.
- <u>Fabricare</u>: It is a laundry services platform currently operating in two cities of Pakistan (Islamabad and Lahore). I had worked on its iOS and Android version. For details please see the iOS app <u>here</u> and android app <u>here</u>.
- NADRA (May 2015 Mar 2016)

Mobile Application Developer

NADRA is a government organisation in Pakistan. My responsibilities include design, develop and maintain a number of Android and iOS applications. Worked on apps related to public relations, financial services, and other government operations. These apps include technologies like biometric verification, facial recognition, and smart card reader. Mostly client-server architecture is followed with major emphasis on user data security and privacy. Below are the few apps I had worked on.

 Worked on a health care Android application that assists medical personal in survey, disease outbreak analysis, and helps in basic record management in remote areas of Pakistan.

- e-sahulat: This is an android tablet app used by franchises to carry out operations like cash transaction to/from branchless accounts, receive cash for government retired personals, utility bill payments, and so on.
- Kissan Relief Package: An android tablet app used by government and nongovernment agencies to carry out distribution of aid packages among farmers in Pakistan.
- NRC Locator: An Android and iOS app for locating, searching NADRA centres inside Pakistan and providing details about centres and providing details about processes involved for a certain task. For details please see <a href="here">here</a>.

#### AppLabs (Aug 2014 - Jan 2015)

Mobile Application Developer

AppLabs is a software development house and during my stay I worked on below mentioned projects.

- Tiinkk: an iOS social network application which aid users in making daily life decisions (related to clothing, style, and fashion) in an interesting way.
- Developed an iPad app for trainers in a private gymnasium which assists and helps manage different trainees. Manages physical status of trainees involved and integrates sale/purchase of related tools.
- Worked on the "Disaster Aware City of Cockburn" Android app. This app was funded by the Australian government and its goal was to cope with natural emergency crises and disasters and make emergency plans ahead of time in case of any emergency. For details please see here.

### • Skylight Software (Apr 2011 - Jul 2014)

Software Engineer

I was part of team that designed & developed a new document format application similar to Microsoft Word. It is a multi-platform application which runs on major platforms (macOS, Windows, and iOS). I contribution was mostly in Mac OS X and iOS platforms. Used WebKit for implementing Inter Process Communication. Other technologies used were Memcached and smart pointers in C++.

- Consultancy, Freelance, Open Source Software and other
  - Developed an iOS app for <u>GlobalRescue</u> which provides immediate rescue services in case of emergency for its clients. The iOS app can be found <u>here</u>.
  - o Pixomatic: This is a photo editing iOS application. For details please see here.
  - A few other iOS and android apps.
  - Please see my GitHub profile to see my contribution to open source.

#### Education

- Master's in Computer Sciences (Sep 2015 Jun 2019)
  National University of Sciences & Technology, Islamabad Pakistan
- Bachelor's in Information & Communication Systems Engineering (Sep 2007 Aug 2011)
  National University of Sciences & Technology, Islamabad Pakistan

# Skills

- iOS
- Android
- Swift
- Objective-C
- Kotlin
- Java
- C/C++
- Python
- Git
- REST API
- JSON

- Database & Persistance
- Core Data
- Networking
- Agile
- Scrum
- Xcode
- Android Studio
- Machine Learning
- Deep Learning
- Computer Vision